我们往南征讨斯巴达克斯叛军
We advance south on Spartacus and those who follow him in rebellion.
让倒向叛军的乱臣贼子
Let our shadow fall upon them and every man,
不分男女老幼 死无葬身之地
woman and child so touched by it, struck from this world.
成交
A bargain well struck.
老子不再是罗马人了
Call me Roman no more then.
足够装备那些加入我们的人
Those that join us are well armed.
你们想要攻占这座城吗
You move to take the fucking city.
受您重托 父亲
You honor me, father.
找到斯巴达克斯 汇报他的动向
Find Spartacus and send word of his movement.
但不要打草惊蛇 等我带主力部队到达
But do not tempt engagement until I have arrived with proper force.
市政官把自己关在粮仓里
The Aedile bars himself in the horreum,
泼满了沥青 还扬言要点燃
spilling pitch and threatens to put light to bear.
不要
No!
这座城是我们的了
The city, is ours.
《斯巴达克斯：诅咒者之战》
《信义男儿》
镣铐变成了剑
Swords born from shackles.
这真是化腐朽为神奇 埃提斯
Your hands turn miracle, Attius.
那你是不是该多给点钱
Then perhaps you would bless them with additional coin,
奖赏我造就的神迹
in reward for such divinity.
我们拿它成就大业 就是给你最好的奖赏
Knowing effort serves higher purpose is reward enough.
你想讨赏 结果碰了一鼻子灰吧
You chew on fresh bargain, only to swallow stale shit.
滚你妈的 你个长头发的娘们
Suck cock, you long-haired woman.
给甘尼克斯搭把手 把刚出炉的货给克雷斯
Aid Gannicus, in delivery of latest offering to Crixus.
你还是留在城里为好
Should you linger within our city,
我们商量一下以后的合作
we shall discuss terms of future benefit.
我不相信那个小坏蛋
I do not lay trust in that little shit.
你谁都不信
You do not lay trust in anyone.
你跟我过来
You come with me!
对罗马人就更不信了
More so when they carry name of Rome.
- 快走 - 没长舌头的傻逼
- Ah, go! - Silent cunt!
卢戈
Lugo.
囚犯怎么样了
How fare our prisoners?
他们的屎尿拉了自己一身
They fucking shit themselves!
不信你来闻
A smell welcome to nose!
保证他们有饭吃
See that they are fed.
这些囚犯 押去哪里
These prisoners? We take them where?
我有疑问 把他们拷在街上有什么用
I question thought of keeping them shackled throughout fucking streets.
只有这个疑问吗
Is that all you question?
我们在打仗 斯巴达克斯
We are at war, Spartacus.
我更愿意看到敌人都死光
I would see our enemy struck to the afterlife.
妇女和孩子都不例外吗
Women and children counted among them?
我们逃出巴蒂塔斯家时 也没放过妇女孩子
Were the same not robbed of life in escape from Batiatus' villa?
攻下这座城时也不例外
Or the taking of this very city?
没错
They were.
但是剩下没死的人就不能不考虑了
Yet few that remain pose no fall to concern.
但这就需要考虑他们的食物
They pose concern to fucking stomach.
消耗我们的粮食
Drawing from our food
市政官泼的沥青就毁了不少
which runs low from Aedile dousing pitch upon grain.
我们去看看库存
Let us gauge our stores.
不要再想没必要的屠杀了
And turn from thought of needless slaughter.
眼睛别离开对手
Keep eye upon your opponent.
看准时机转守为攻
Seek to turn defense into attack.
兵器到了 刚出炉的
More steel, forged towards purpose.
斯巴达克斯答应给他的钱
He has been paid what Spartacus promised,
已经给了吧
for aiding taking the city?
五千第纳尔
Five thousand denarii.
我玩命挣的
Well earned.
那他怎么还留在城里碍眼
Then why does he yet darken presence within our walls?
回话啊 我懒得传话
Give answer. I'm not fucking echo.
继续协助你们成就大业
To further lend hand to your cause.
走之前还能挣更多钱
The promise of gathering more coin
我当然要好好考虑
before taking leave also weighs consideration.
妮维雅 纳西尔
Naevia! Nasir!
去把武器分发给能用的人
See those of skill to proper weapon.
你的路费
For your journey.
我一醒来就想要男人
I wake with desire for cock.
你又不在床上
Yet you from bed.
我是透明人吗
Am I turn from the fucking visible?
我起得早 去找埃提斯了
I rose early, slip to Attius.
很值得
Much deserve for his service.
跑来一只跟屁虫
Cause bring fucking shadow.
我干掉她主人后
The girl follows heel like errant pup,
她就像迷路的小狗跟来了
since I took her master's life.
躲开
Clear a fucking path.
快点走
Keep moving!
靠着墙
Against the wall!
坐下
Sit here!
闭嘴
And shut mouth!
你妻子怀孕了
Your wife is with child.
她需要补补身子
She should not be absent nourishment.
多谢
Gratitude.
别弄错了
You mistake intent.
我不是施舍给你
I do not offer charity,
是跟你交易
I offer exchange.
面包
Bread,
换我们还没有找到的钱
for whatever coin you may know of yet undiscovered.
说不定就藏在你的哪间小屋里
Perhaps within walls of your own little hovel?
粮仓西边 两条街外
Two streets west of the horreum.
门上有乌尔比安的名字
The name Ulpianus the above door.
屋子里的桌脚是空的
Inside, leg of table stands hollow.
里面有我所有的钱
You will find all that I have there.
还有吗
Any more offerings?
没有了
No?
很好
Very well then.
等等
Wait.
面包 给我妻子的
The bread. For my wife…
抱歉
Apologies.
谁更饿
Who's more hungry?
你想见血吗
Do you wish to see blood?
有人要饿死了
Someone will starve!
混蛋
You cunt!
你们想见血吗
Do you desire blood?
想 想
Yeah!! Yeah!
那就来一场公平竞争
Then let us have proper contest!
拿剑来
Bring swords!
我认识那人
I know that one.
乌尔比安 面包师
Ulpianus, a baker of breads.
他不是战士 也不是冷血的人
He is no fighter, nor man of distant heart.
我们要玩这种无聊的游戏吗
We fall to fucking games now?
罗马人逼迫你和克雷斯角斗 也是为了玩
The Romans forced you and Crixus to such, for their amusement.
我们只是以牙还牙
We but return favor.
求你了 我不会打
I beg you… I have no skill in this.
他不会打
Oh, he has no skill in this.
罗马渣滓
This is Roman cunt!
这就是胜利者的奖赏
Let the victor, claim their bounty!
失败者
And the sea the fallen,
就跟进城时杀的罗马人黄泉相见
to join the Roman dead which we have swept from this city!
不要
No!
开始
Begin.
上啊 开始
Go! Begin!
干掉他
Get at him!
要见血
Draw blood!
乌尔比安
Ulpianus!
打啊 干掉他
Come on! Get at him!
不要 乌尔比安
No, Ulpianus!
这种角斗真是不够看
A fight far from worthy arena.
但奖励还是会给
But promise was made.
耶
Yeah!
享受你的荣誉吧
Feast upon laurels.
该死的混蛋
You fucking shit…
他想拿剑 从背后攻击你
He reached for sword to strike when you presented back!
他只是去拿吃的 你这个疯女人
He was reaching for the food, you mad cunt!
闭嘴 不然就拔掉你的舌头
Hold tongue, or see it ripped from fucking head.
冷静 兄弟
Take pause, brother.
埃提斯是我们一边的
Attius stands with us.
他替该死的罗马人说话
He stands a fucking Roman.
这人不管对奴隶还是对谁 从不耀武扬威
The man has never raised voice in anger, to slave, or any other.
你的朋友们这样做
How do your friends differ,
跟他们眼里的那些渣滓有什么区别
from the fucking villain they brand me?
他是去拿面包吗
Was he reaching for the bread?
我不信
I did not think it.
如果是你弄错了呢
And what if you were mistaken?
有什么区别
The result the same.
决不允许罗马人威胁到我们
A Roman that shall never raise hand against us.
我对罗马人没有任何感情
I have never held love for any of such name,
- 但他对我们没威胁 - 他那种人威胁最大
- yet he held no threat - Men such as him hold the greatest.
表面和善可亲 往往一肚子坏水
True intent, shrouded behind mask of kind and gentle face.
你见过这样的人
Have you known his reflection?
在我去卢卡尼亚矿区之前
Before I came to the mines of Lucania.
有一个名叫海瑞斯的人
This one carried gentle name of Herius.
有妻子 和两个小女儿
Husband. Father of two young daughters.
他给我吃的 让我洗澡
He saw me fed. Bathed.
我在离开巴蒂塔斯家后
Allowed me to feel safe for the first time since being turned
第一次感觉到安全
from the House of Batiatus.
等他家人都睡了后 他来找我
When his family took to sleep, he came to me.
把我抱起来
Lifting me in his arms.
刚开始我还以为是在做梦
I thought it a dream at first.
那个地方
There was a place,
离他的宅子很远
removed from the grounds of his villa,
那里是制作和修理马车的地方
where wagons were crafted and repaired.
他在我身上用了很多工具
He applied his many tools inside me.
最后到处都沾满了血肉
Before turning them to outward flesh.
我希望能抓住你的记忆
I wish I had power to seize memory,
将它彻底赶出你的生活
and with hands strip it from life.
那不是最让我难过的部分
It is not the one that shadows mind.
我在晨光中看到的情景
What I saw in morning light,
才是一生难忘的阴影
forever darkens thought.
那个男人
The man himself,
用亲吻和温暖的笑容
greeting his wife
问候妻子
with kiss and warm smile.
他的女儿在他膝上欢笑
His daughters laughing upon his knee.
前一晚那个嗜血的野兽
The beast from the previous night transformed,
摇身变成了最温柔的男人
into a man who held no threat.
我无话可说
I have no words.
你不需要说话
You do not need them.
只用知道 你在我身边给了我安慰
Knowing, you are at my side gives comfort enough.
我永远都不离开你
I will always stand so.
所有的粮食都成这样了
All the fucking stalls bear same misfortune.
剩下的呢
And of the remainder?
- 够我们吃多久 - 两周
- How long will it see us fed? - Two weeks.
也许可以更久
Perhaps more,
如果我们 省着用 而且人数不增加
if we're cautious and our numbers do not swell.
真他妈见鬼
Fuck the gods.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus.
码头有船停靠
Ships weigh anchor off our coast.
看来有人注意到我们了
It seems we have drawn notice.
赛纳斯
Sanus.
你看到什么了
What do your eyes fall upon?
有四个人过来 全副武装
Four men approach. Armed.
有个人扛着一只桶
One with cask perched atop shoulder.
罗马人吗
Romans?
外表看起来不大像
Not fucking likely, by appearance.
打开门
Raise the gate.
这他妈什么人
What shit is this?
西利西亚的强盗
Brigands of Cilicia.
海盗
Pirates?
我要跟这里管事的人说话
I would speak with the man that has claimed this city.
他正在听你说话
Your words fall upon his ear.
来这儿有何贵干
What business do you break?
你就是斯巴达克斯
You are Spartacus?
正是本人
I stand so named.
就是你搞垮了卡普亚竞技场
The same fiend that brought down the arena in Capua?
在维苏威大败葛雷博
Defeated Glaber at Vesuvius?
给共和国和罗马人造成了难以估量的伤害
Wrought untold suffering upon the Republic and its people.
这是我的荣耀
All deeds claimed with pride.
那我就当你是兄弟
Then I call you fucking brother!
一起畅饮美酒
Let us share gift of wine,
痛骂我们共同的敌人
and break words towards common enemy!
盖乌斯
Gaius!
多年不见
It has been too many years.
岁月不饶人啊 老友
They have been unkind to you, old friend.
至少我不像一头毛茸茸的山羊
At least I do not stand woolly fucking goat!
克拉苏不让我刮脸
Crassus denies me sharpened blade.
为什么
Under what purpose?
他的想法
A personal matter,
只有他信任的人才知道
concerning only those within his confidence.
可惜这儿没这种人
Regrettably none stand so here.
你提前收到了我们到来的消息吗 莫姆缪斯
You have received message in advance of our arrival, Mummius?
我们准备好了 等你下令就出发
We stand ready to march upon your command.
在此之前先用我的营帐吧
Have use of my tent until such a time.
来
Come!
让小子们留在这里谋划
I would leave these boys to their plotting
你来给我说说安东尼乌斯的情况
and hear of your adventures with Antonius.
真是放肆
Impudent shit.
他把你晾在一边 去舔恺撒的鸡巴
He brushes you aside in favor of swallowing Caesar's cock.
但愿噎不死他
Let us pray he chokes upon it.
阿德贝尔
Adherbal!
把桶打开 我们畅饮美酒
Break open cask so we may share drink.
我们先谈谈吧
I would break words in advance.
现在还没有搞清楚状况
While mind is yet unclouded.
赫拉克里奥是你的客人
Heracleo is your guest,
我是你的仆从
and I am at your will.
你他妈的本事这么大 能偷一座城
It is an honor for me to be across from the man
能见到你是我的荣幸
who steals an entire fucking city!
是该死的罗马人偷了我们的自由
It was the fucking Romans who stole freedom from us.
我们只是拿回我们应有的
We merely seize what is owed.
我喜欢你们的说法 兄弟
I favor turn of your reason, brothers.
希留爱沙还有罗马人活着
Some Romans yet live within Sinuessa?
有一些
A few.
市政官也活着吗
The Aedile among them?
没有
He does not.
- 确定吗 - 我们占了他的宅子
- You are sure of this? - His villa now stands ours.
是我亲手解决了他
His claim to it severed by my own hand.
那我也受伤了
Then I too have been injured.
这人说话总他妈兜圈子
This man speaks in fucking riddles.
有话直说
Straighten tongue,
不然就滚
or fall from presence.
市政官跟我有个协议
The Aedile and I had an arrangement.
他跟你这种人做生意
He brokered such with men of your calling?
当然不是公开的
Openly, no.
很多事情都是暗地里进行的
Yet many things are born of dark corners.
大海充满了危险
The seas are fraught with dangers…
尤其是对那些
especially for those who,
把他当成敌手的人
consider themselves his competitor.
怎么回报你们的服务
In return for your "Services"?
透露那些可怜的船只何时起航 走哪条线
Knowledge of time and route of unfortunate vessels.
船上的货物 算到我的货物里
All goods aboard, added to my own,
再在这份新的清单上
with the seal of the Aedile
加盖市政官的公章
pressed upon new manifest.
盗贼为什么要跟协议和公章扯上关系
What cause does thief upon wave need of parchment and seal?
在大港口交易来历不明的货物
The official seal removes unwanted attention when
公章可以减少不必要的麻烦
trading acquisitions in respected ports.
结果你们这一动手
Advantage snatched from hand,
我们的好处也没了
by fucking action of your own.
皮笑肉不笑的操蛋家伙
To shit with this grinning cunt.
- 艾力冈 - 他有什么能耐
- Agron. - What threat does he hold?
在海上朝我们撒尿
Pissing on us from the sea?
等尿到你身上可别吓坏了 小子
You would be surprised by the reach of my stream, boy.
我们都冷静一下
Let's us take breath then,
说话都注意一点
remove ourselves from heated words.
来喝酒吧
There is yet drink to be had.
等月亮升起再过来吧
Return when sun gives way to moon.
到时候再看有没有举杯的理由
And discover if there stands cause to share cup.
听凭吩咐 斯巴达克斯大王
As you command, King Spartacus.
听凭吩咐
As you command.
这人还真他妈的牛逼哄哄
The man swings cock to rival Jupiter himself.
关上城门 把他结果了
Close gate upon ass, and be done with him.
这人也许还有用
He may yet be of use.
找到市政官的印章
Find Aedile's seal,
我们看看有没有什么好处
and let us weigh advantage it brings.
西利西亚人
Cilicians!
满嘴都是屎
Shit rises to fill mouth.
你到底见没见过
Have you laid eyes upon it or not?
我只管打铁 不是码头的生意人
I forge steel, not trade at fucking ports.
我要市政官的印章有什么用
What need would I have of Aedile's seal?
早说不就完了
Words I would have greeted sooner.
你赢得自由之前
Is that what it was like,
就是这样子吗
before you gained your freedom?
你生来就是像野兽一样打斗吗
Were you made to fight as an animal would,
就像对待可怜的乌尔比安那样
as you made poor Ulpianus?
- 不是我要耍他 - 但你没有阻止
- I prompted no contest. - Yet you did not stop it.
当你决定帮助我们夺城时
What fate did you believe
以为现在是什么样子
when deciding to aid in taking the city?
我别无选择
I held no fucking choice.
任何人在任何时候都有选择
Every man holds such at time's end.
你不喜欢那些人 埃提斯
You hold no love for these people, Attius.
现在就不要假装慈悲了
Do not now raise vaunted concerns now.
这些人
"These people."
他们是罗马人 我不是吗
Am I not Roman, as they were?
我和那些幸存者不一样
As some yet are?
你只代表自己
You stand for yourself alone.
我也如此
As I once stood.
你已经证明了
You are proof then.
最低贱的泥土
That basest clay
都可能塑造成价值连城的东西
may yet be molded into something of worth.
忘了过去
Turn from past,
展望全新的未来
set eye toward new horizon,
远走高飞 改头换面
far from this place and the man that you were.
赞美诸神 终于找到能说上话的人了
Praise fucking gods, I've found men of worth.
你是从什么地方来的
What crude form do you deposit at feet?
希留爱沙
Sinuessa.
斯巴达克斯占领了希留爱沙山
Spartacus has taken Sinuessa en Valle.
传莫姆缪斯
Summon Mummius.
酒
Wine.
多谢
Gratitude.
那就给我们有价值的消息
Repay favor with gift of words.
没什么特别有价值的
I have few of note.
我们以为城门关好了
We thought the gate secure.
可斯巴达克斯是从地狱来的魔鬼
Yet Spartacus is of the underworld,
他能穿过木头和石头
able to spirit himself through wood and stone.
他不过是个凡人
He is but a man.
我亲眼见过他
I've laid eyes upon him.
浑身是血和伤 整座城都为之颤抖
Bathed in blood and gore. The city trembling in his wake.
斯巴达克斯不是凡人 他是死神
Spartacus is no man. He's the Bringer of Death.
你不是还活着吗
And yet you live.
看来你的战斗技能跟那个传奇人物不相上下
Your skill in combat must equal that of the legend himself.
市政官给了我一点钱帮着执行宵禁命令
I was paid but a few coin by the Aedile to aid in curfew.
- 我不是士兵 - 别管这个了
- I'm no soldier. - Put such question aside.
斯巴达克斯手下有多少人
How many men does Spartacus now hold?
我不知道
I do not know.
他们的人挤满了街道 一路上见人就杀
The streets were filled with them, slaughtering all in their path.
我赶在他们抢占码头之前逃了出来
I barely made escape to the bay before they took the docks.
现在都清楚了
Now it becomes clear.
你不愿意英勇战死 而选择逃跑
In place of falling a hero, you chose to flee.
当个懦夫
And fall a coward.
你疯了吗
Have you lost mind?
这人没有用处 他自己说的
The man held no worth, by his own tongue.
这里不归你管事
You are not in fucking command.
抱歉
Apologies.
我走神了
I slip from reason…
见到不争气的下属就控制不住脾气
when presented with the faults of lesser men.
我们先清理尸体 再商讨…
Let us see body removed, and discuss
不用商讨什么了
The time for words has ended.
拔营
Break camp,
回去跟我父亲报告斯巴达克斯的消息
and return to my father with news of Spartacus.
他命令我守在你身边
He gave order to remain at your side.
我代马科斯•克拉苏行使权力
I am the word and the will of Marcus Crassus.
你不在我身边 盖乌斯
You are not at my side, Gaius.
你在我之下
You serve beneath me.
那便遵命
I fall to command.
召集你的手下
Gather what remains of your men.
我们向希留爱沙山进军
We move for Sinuessa en Valle.
我们把宅子翻了两遍 还是一无所获
We have seached the villa twice upon, and with empty hands.
漫无目的地找肯定不行
Seach horn give lack result.
那就去告诉赫拉克里奥 让他滚回海上去
Let send word to Heracleo, return to the fucking sea.
我不想操之过急
I would not beat so quick.
这件事我同意艾力冈
I'm with Agron in this.
我不喜欢西利西亚人的眼神
I do not care looking at Cilicians' eye.
他有我们没有的东西
Yet he has what we do not.
船只 可以运送粮食和补给
Ships. Ships can carry grain and supplies.
就算克拉苏对陆地进行了封锁
Even when upon land blocked by Crassus.
他要的东西找不到 我们如何交易
And how do we strike bargain absent what he seeks.
纳美特斯那边怎么样 你问过没有
What of Nemetes? Have you broken words?
他也没有看到印章
He is not lay eyes upon the seal.
他还在大海捞针一样地找
Spare picking bones the city clean seach the very coin.
纯属白费力气
We waste effort.
我们没有人能发现秘密藏好的东西
There is no one among us can divine words with secret.
那我只能求人了
Then I should entreat miracle.
从贵族下手
Of lofty standing.
都出去
Leave us.
这是我家
This stood my home.
不再是了
No longer.
我不愿意求饶
I will not beg for my life.
我不要你的命
I do not seek it.
只要你帮忙
Only your aid.
你杀了我夫君
You rob me of my husband.
糟蹋我的城市
Lay waste to my city.
你现在还想要我帮忙
And now you call upon fucking aid?
我们在打仗
We are at war.
你们有死有伤再正常不过
You and your people stand casualty.
我们的人并不想留一个活口
My own ranks question sparing a few that yet draw breath.
而我要证明留你们活命是对的
I give chance to prove wisdom of it.
那我们就该像你们的玩物一样
So we may live out our days
取悦你们 供你们消遣吗
as party favors for your fucking amusement?
就像乌尔比安一样
As word carries of Ulpianus?
乌尔比安
Ulpianus?
你的人让他为了一块面包去决斗
Your men made him fight for crust of bread.
虽然他打赢了 还是砍了他一只手
And claimed hand even though he stood victor.
我并不知道这事
A thing I did not know of.
这种事不会再发生了
It shall not pass again.
我曾经信任过你
I took belief in your reassurance once before.
你却杀了我的夫君
And now stand widow for it.
我做的事由我担当
I do not turn from what I have done.
他为人正直
He was an honorable man!
却让你给杀了
Forever stricken from this world by you!
你太抬举他了
You elevate the dead beyond their worth.
你又不了解他
You did not know him.
你也不了解他
Nor I fear did you.
认识赫拉克里奥这个人吗
The name Heracleo holds meaning?
这人是海上的恶霸
A plague upon the sea.
我夫君重金悬赏他的人头
My husband devoted much coin toward his capture.
你夫君为了更大的好处
He devoted greater sum,
与他签订秘密协议
towards secret pact.
你撒谎
You lie.
你夫君以公章为条件
Your husband provided seal of office
利用他除去对手
in exchange for dispatching of his rivals.
这是赫拉克里奥亲手给我的
Presented to me by Heracleo himself.
我并不想破坏你对他的美好印象
Know that I do not take pleasure in staining cherished memory.
你毁了我的整个世界 还要装好人
You tear world from grasp, and whisper of kindness.
我是给你一个机会
I whisper of opportunity.
赫拉克里奥需要市政官的印章
Heracleo seeks the Aedile's seal.
有了印章 我就可以交易来粮食
With it I will forge trade that will see us fed.
你找不到印章的
It eludes discovery.
你知道印章在哪里
You know of the seal's location?
恩尼乌斯害怕有人叛乱
Ennius feared rebellion,
所以把他的东西保管得很严
and took measure to protect what was his.
他在这座城中有无数个
There are many places hidden to eye
秘密贮藏点
among his holdings throughout the city.
帮我找出来
Aid in revealing them,
我们从西利西亚人那里交易来的好处
and you and your people will share equal portion
肯定也有你们的一份
from what we gain in bargain with the Cilician.
我要获得自由
I would have freedom as price.
我们所有人
For all of us.
找到印章
Do this thing,
当我们离开希留爱沙山后
and you will be released,
你们就自由了
when we take leave of Sinuessa.
我怎么才能相信你
Am I to trust your word?
很简单
The reason is simple.
你没得选择
You stand absent choice.
居然藏在守护神的赤瞳里
Hidden within blushed eye, the guardian spirits.
难怪诸神要遗弃你的丈夫 和这座城市呢
Is it a wonder the gods turned on your husband and this fucking city?
过去的不要再提 还是谈我们的生意吧
Let us turn from past and set gaze towards favored bargain.
还要痛快喝个够
And fall to much needed drink!
你开价多少
How much would you have for it?
我什么都不要
I ask for nothing.
等我们离开这座城后
Upon our abandoning the city,
这印章就归你了
the seal is yours.
在此之前呢
And until such fated day?
订一个贸易协议
An agreement of trade.
以钱换粮
Coin for food.
你船上的头一批货给我们
First shipment from what stores you have aboard your ships.
你这是在要求波塞冬脱裤子露屁股
You would entreat Poseidon to shun robes and present ass!
如果他在这里我就敢
If he stood before me.
可惜他不在
Yet he does not.
我的货品质上乘
My supplies are of finest quality.
在港口很容易卖到一万八千第纳尔
Eighteen thousand denarii easily fetched if sold at port.
没有印章的话呢
Absent the Aedile's seal?
你这人真是不可理喻
You are not the man one expects.
一万第纳尔
Ten thousand denarii.
再加上市政官的老婆
If Aedile's wife is added to the bargain huh.
我不是罗马人
You mistake me for a Roman.
我不做奴隶贸易
I do not trade in slaves.
这样的美人 换我也不卖
Nor would I, if possessed with such a ripe cunt.
一万两千第纳尔
Twelve thousand denarii.
日出前一小时
In hour before sun's rising,
到城外的岸边交易
upon landing beyond city walls.
城外
Beyond the city?
陆地太不安全了 兄弟
Ground absent advantage, brother.
我可不愿意冒险把船开进港
I would not sail into port, only to be set upon.
那就城外
Beyond city walls.
日出前一小时
In hour before sun rises.
那就定了
It is settled then.
这下总可以喝个痛快了吧
Now may we have fucking drink?! Huh!
赫拉克里奥带来的什么狗屁酒
What fucking piss does Heracleo offer?
苦艾酒
Absinthe, by name.
我有次一下子喝了六杯
I once drained six cups,
然后跟一只幻想中的猫吵得不可开交
and found myself in heated argument with imaginary cat.
那就在你离开罗马海岸之前
Then let us drain seven, and finish argument
再喝个七杯 跟它吵完为止
before you strike from Roman shores.
好
Yes.
盯着别人的男人看
Dangerous thing.
是一件很危险的事情
Eyes upon man not your own.
对不起 我无意冒犯
Apologies. I meant no offense.
你想和他共享鱼水之欢吗
You want his cock inside you?
快说 你这小东西
Speak, little thing.
纳美特斯人 你这孬种
Nemetes, you cock eater!
他救了我
He saved my life.
我只是想谢谢他
I desire only to thank him.
过来
Come.
我们好好聊两句
我可不鸟这些西利西亚人
I do not care for these Cilicians.
可罗马人很喜欢他们
Yet they are preferred to Romans.
我的鸡巴有魔力
My cock is magic.
从我面前消失
Then see it vanish from sight.
再来
More wine!
你真是个笨蛋
You're a fool.
竟然相信一个言而无信之徒
To lay trust in one stitched of lies and deceit.
我不是第一次跟这种人打交道
I'm no stranger to his kind.
原以为我也是这样
I thought myself so.
可我到现在还放不下
Yet now replay every moment.
我夫君生前对我的每一次爱抚
Every touch my husband laid upon me.
背后却隐藏着残酷的真相
Questioning truth behind them.
这是诸神对我愚蠢无知的惩罚
The gods punish me for being so blind.
不如让赫拉克里奥带走我
Would that you had let Heracleo take me,
让我承受诸神的愤怒
to see their wrath complete.
我不信你的神
I place no stock in your gods.
也不要那些无辜的人
Nor any that would seek injury
经受什么诸神的惩罚
for crimes against those undeserving.
我已经下令
I have given command
你可以在城里自由活动
that you are free to move about city.
作为回报
In return,
你要帮我
you will lend hand
确保那些罗马人填饱肚子
in seeing your people receive proper share of food.
如果有人遭受虐待 你就来通知我
And carry word to me if any should fall to mistreatment.
真令人惊讶
It surprises,
这小小的镣铐压得人喘不过气来
how such small a weight bears such heavy burden.
所有反抗罗马的人都知道这一点
A truth known to all who take up arms against Rome.
你就睡在这里吧
You shall sleep where you are.
他们如果知道我睡在这里
My people will turn from me,
一定会背弃我的
if I'm known to bed beneath your roof.
我夫君在城边有一个马厩
My husband held stable at edge of city.
我要住到那里去
I would take shelter within its walls.
我只是想让你住得舒适些
I sought only to provide comfort.
赫拉克里奥说对了
Heracleo spoke the truth,
至少有一件事说对了
at least upon one subject.
你这人真是不可理喻
You are not the man one expects.
抱歉
Apologies.
喝了这杯 我就原谅你
Share drink, and see them accepted.
我要跟别人喝
My cup is spoken for.
我的兴趣不在于你喝我的酒
I seek not to claim it my own.
而在于双唇之间的甘露
Merely grace lips with its nectar.
你这话很放肆
You are bold of words.
我在海上待太久了
I have been too long at sea
跟粗人混在一起
among, rough company.
我不喜欢大风大浪
I do not favor crashing waves.
只要你开口
Words from mouth such as yours
我就永不再回到海上
could move a man to forever turn from them.
你他妈的放手
Remove fucking hand.
他没有恶意
He meant no harm.
抱歉
Apologies.
我不知道一朵鲜花插在莱茵河东 一坨牛粪上
I did not know you were mired in shit east of the Rhine.
揍他
Smash him!
艾力冈
Agron!
离开这儿
Fall from sight.
这欢宴有点不和谐了
Revelry has struck sour note.
我不希望无谓的争吵给我们之间造成裂隙
I would not have senseless quarrel open gap between us.
那就在我们交易之时
Then see it filled with coin
带足银子
at appointed hour.
看看我们这次合作牢不牢靠
And we shall test sureness of our footing.
宴会搞成这样 斯巴达克斯很不高兴
Spartacus stands displeased with celebration's end.
这不是我挑起的事端
I was not the one who caused offense.
西利西亚人是过分了
The Cilician overstepped,
但是你的反应也…
yet your response was
理应如此
Was as it fucking should be.
就算是朱庇特敢动你 我也要让他悔青肠子
Jupiter himself would find cause to tremble if he laid hand upon you.
你为了我敢向神宣战
You would battle a god for me?
我会杀死
I would slay all
所有敢将你从我怀中抢走的人
that would lay attempt to wrest you from my arms.
别想什么朱庇特和西利西亚人了
Strike Jupiter and the Cilician from mind.
跟你比起来 他们都一文不值
I would have them of no concern to the one that holds my heart.
你一言不发就走了
You left absent word.
刚才有人打架
There was a fight.
弄得很吵
It was very loud.
我去料理那只跟屁虫了
I leave to make shadow flesh.
撩拨欲火
and to bring desire.
为你
For you.
过来
Come.
穿上衣服出去
Gather your robes and leave us.
走
Go.
不喜欢她吗
She does not please?
她只是个孩子
She is but a child.
我还是喜欢成熟的女人
And I would have a woman tend to my needs,
在我跟斯巴达克斯走之前…
in brief hours before I move with Spartacus…
抱歉
Apologies.
我有话想说
I would have words.
还是别说了
I would not.
你没给我说谢谢的机会
You've not given opportunity towards gratitude.
我还活着都是因为你
I yet draw breath because of you.
你的主人是死在战场上的
Your dominus fell to an act of war.
他死在天赐的英雄手里
He fell to a hero sent by the gods.
英雄连你名字都不记得
One that does not even recall your name.
我叫希贝儿
My name is Sibyl.
希贝儿
Sibyl.
你觉得你亏欠我的 希贝儿
And you feel you owe debt Sibyl?
我的一切都是拜你所赐
I owe you everything.
想还债
Then see it repaid
就离我 还有我这样的人
by staying far from my presence.
远点
And men of my kind.
你要把我辛苦赚来的都收走
You would claim all that I have earned?
都是你偷来的
All you have stolen.
攻占这座城的时候 我不也和兄弟们并肩
Did I not stand with my brothers when city was taken,
与你同生共死吗
risking life beside you?
我在维苏威那些战斗中
As I did in shadow of Vesuvius
不都他妈的这么干吗
and every fucking battle since?
所有的人都这样
As all that follow cause.
不光你一个人在牺牲
Know that you do not stand alone in sacrifice.
那铁匠呢
And what of the blacksmith?
你给他的钱也收走了吗
Did you seize coin given him as well?
这是命令 不是闲聊
You mistake command for conversation.
给我去干正事
Fall to your purpose.
钱在你手里吗
You carry the balance?
在他手里
He does.
甘尼克斯去哪儿了
Where is Gannicus?
他歪歪倒倒的
He comes upon heel.
没剩几分力气了
What is left of him.
托图斯
Totus!
干正事
Fall to task.
我们定好了
We are committed.
纳西尔 守好城墙
Nasir, take position upon wall.
我想跟你在一起
I would stand with you.
快去
Go.
我很快就回来
I shall return shortly.
一旦城门在我们身后关上
Once gate closes behind us,
没我的话谁也不许开门
do not see it raised short of my word.
再不走就撑不住了
Terms of stroll worsen by passing moment.
当心有人叛变
Keep watchful eye towards sign of betrayal.
我倒想要他们试试
I pray they make fucking attempt.
要是赫拉克里奥和他手下
If Heracleo and his men,
背信弃义
prove short of honor…
那便就地处决
kill them where they stand.
打开城门
Raise the gate!
看着像西利西亚人
Cilicians, by the look.
他们为什么在希留爱沙城外登陆
Why would they take landing outside Sinuessa?
谈判
To seek alliance.
斯巴达克斯敢跟他们打交道
Spartacus stands the fool
那他就真蠢到家了
if he risks dealings with such as them.
他们这帮毛贼就是臭味相投
They are thieves of equal nature.
如果他们达成协议 那我父亲围城的计划
And if they come to terms it would prevent my father
可就要失败了
from starving the rebels out.
我决不会让这种事发生
A thing I will not have fall to pass.
莫姆缪斯 让你的人准备进攻
Mummius, prepare your men to advance.
进攻
Advance?
听老子号令行事
Fall to fucking command.
提比略 你父亲明确下令
Tiberius, your father gave strict order
不许与斯巴达克斯正面交锋
not to engage Spartacus.
我父亲要的是能打仗的狼
My father desires a wolf of battle,
不是亦步亦趋的狗
not a well-heeled dog.
今晚我要用鲜血与死亡
And this night I shall honor him
为他争光
with blood and death.
我们完全没有掩护
We are too exposed.
斯巴达克斯他们离开城墙
Spartacus and his men more so,
比我们更无依无靠
beyond the walls of his city.
他们出了城门
They spill from gate.
听我号令
Upon my signal only.
绝不能为了一时疑心坏了大事
I would give no errant cause to doubt intention.
纳西尔 你看到了什么
Nasir, what do you see?
屁都没有
Shit and piss.
太远 天又太黑
They are too far in darkness.
她说什么
What does she say?
罗马人…决斗的那人…跑了
Roman your man make fight gone.
乌尔比安
Ulpianus?
跟他的肥婆还有关押在一起的跑了
With fat wife and others chained with him.
必须搜索全城
We must sweep the city
不 你们留下
No. Remain here.
有可能是声东击西 想让我们远离城门
It may be distraction, to draw us from the gate.
你要去哪儿
Where do you go?
你好好站你的岗
Do not tear eyes from purpose!
给你
Your price.
我们说好的价钱
As agreed upon.
无意冒犯 不过这也…
Apologies, I mean no offense, yet ah…
打开看看
Open it.
你果真言而有信
You stand a man of your word.
当今世道你这种人不多见了
A very rare thing, in such a world.
更稀罕的是
Rarer yet,
能与我匹敌的对手
to greet my equal.
卡斯特斯 艾德赫伯
Castus. Adherbal.
把该给这些兄弟的东西都拿来
Bring our brothers what they are owed.
你连句告别的话都没有
You take leave of the city?
就要离开吗
Absent parting words?
我跟需要告别的人说过了
I've broken them to all that matter.
要是跟西利西亚人的交易做成了
If dealings with the Cilicians end as desired,
老子就花钱买路 离你们远远的
I will buy passage far from your fucking presence.
你也为你的朋友们花这笔钱吗
Do you buy such for your friends as well?
我朋友
Friends?
告诉我他们在哪儿
Tell me where there are.
等等 我不知道你在说什么
Wait! I do not know what you speak of!
我说的是罗马人 你他妈的背叛了我们
I speak of Romans. And your fucking treachery.
去你妈的
Fuck!
你要杀人
You wish for blood?
放马过来
Come then.
比起拴着锁链的面包师
And find greater challenge than that
我没那么容易对付
of a simple crafter of bread in fucking chains.
就这
This,
你一共就这点东西
this stands the sum of your offerings?
诸神操蛋 当然不是
Fuck the gods, no!
就是让你先看看
A mere sample for your approval.
剩下的都在船上
The remainder lies aboard my ships,
太多了 一艘小船运不过来
too great a cargo to ferry by skiff.
现在我收了钱
Now that payment has been received,
就可以开船进港了
I shall sail into port
这不是我们说好的
That was not the arrangement.
抱歉让你糊涂了
Apologies, if you fell to confusion.
去你妈的抱歉
Fuck your apologies.
都别动
Hold ground!
你怎么想
What are your thoughts?
我真是蠢到家了
That I stand the fool.
居然跟没信义的人做交易
For laying trust in a man absent honor.
也许是时候 让我们就此分道扬镳
Then perhaps the time has come. For us to…
永不相见
forever part ways…
我们中计了
We are betrayed!
不是我干的
This is not my hand!
操蛋的海盗
Fucking pirates!
进攻
Advance!
罗马军队
Romans!
莫姆缪斯死哪儿去了
Where the fuck is Mummius?!
我操
Fuck!
我对你们这种人
I have had my fill…
早就受够了
of men such as you…
莫姆缪斯
Mummius?
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
又有军队过来了
More come!
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus…
进攻
Attack!
盾牌阵
Testudo!
装弹
Load!
发射
Fire!
我他妈的没警告过你老子射程远吗
Did I not warn you of my fucking reach!
早警告过你们了
I warned you!
- 都别动 - 撤退
- Stand ground! - Retreat!
都他妈的给老子坚守阵地
Stand your fucking ground!
撤退
Retreat!
托图斯
Totus!
必须撤兵了
We must retreat.
- 不 - 我不能让你送死
- No… - I will not see you fall!
快追
After them!
让他们跑吧
Let them go!
我们得马上回城
We must return to the city! Now!
撤退
Retreat!
你现在怎么看 斯巴达克斯大王
How stand your thoughts now, King Spartacus?
把钱拿着
Take coin.
开船进港
And see your ships to port.
来吧
Come!
走
We go!
我还以为你死在外头了
I thought you gone from this world.
我可不会那么轻易就离开你
You will not so easily see me from your arms.
我想去支援你们
I attempted to come to your aid.
纳美特斯人和他那群混蛋不给我开门
Nemetes and his shits would not open gate.
如果城门被攻破 死的人就更多
If gate had been breached, more would have fallen.
他不过是遵令行事
He but followed command.
我不明白为什么罗马派个臭小子带这么点人
Confounds why the Romans attacked in such small numbers,
就来攻打我们
led by a boy.
根本没道理啊
It holds no sense.
死人身上能找到答案
Answer lay among the dead.
我们认敌为友
And those we mistakenly name friend.
他先动手的
He came at me,
我问他为什么要帮乌尔比安
when confronted with question of aiding Ulpianus
和其他在逃的人
and the others in escape.
你别无选择
You were left absent choice.
他出手帮助我们夺城
Would he lend hand in taking city,
就是为了拿性命开玩笑吗
only to risk life in such attempt?
他只是想把低贱的泥土 塑造成有价值的东西
He but sought to form basest clay, into something of worth.
还有比这更重要的事
There stands matters of more pressing concern.
搜索全城 找到乌尔比安和其他人
Let us sweep city for Ulpianus and the others.
不能让罗马人密谋添乱
I would not have Romans plotting beneath foot,
造成更大的损失
or seeking greater harm.
多谢
Gratitude.
这里还有
There's more over here.